

Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com www.LondonResearchInternational.com

Mr. Olaniran

NATIONALITY: Nigeria

SUMMARY

I have broad experience in environmental hydrogeology and geohydrology. My emphasis has been groundwater/borehole drilling, water sampling and soil sampling and characterization where I have been involved in planning and conducting fieldwork, data analysis, and report preparation for clients.

I have experience in geophysical(hydrogeophysical) and geotechnical soil investigation/geotechnical boring..

I have also designed, managed, supervised, drilled various diameter borehole/wells and wellfields in different sedimentary formations & basement complex of variable depths (between 20m—600m).

I has considerable field experience. My field drilling experience includes hollow stem auger borings(hand drilling/tripod drilling), geotechnical borings/drilling, core drilling, and reverse circulation drilling(used motorized mobile drilling rigs), monitoring of wells,borehole development using air compressor(air lifting) installation of surface & submersible pumps. I have been involved in collecting, analyzing and interpreting soil samples, groundwater samples, and surface water samples. I have experience in drilling test holes, conducted well aquifer tests, and oil & gas drilling. I was involved in the soil investigation of a groundwater and soil contamination for an oil spillage.

I have also involved in impact mitigation monitoring(IMM) for soil, surface water, groundwater (regular samplings) and air quality in a cement mining quarry. I have considerable experience in turnkey rural water supply schemes, water treatment and pipework reticulation.

EDUCATION

AHMADU BELLO UNIVERSITY,ZARIA,NIGERIA. 1989. B.SC(HONS) GEOLOGY.



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com www.LondonResearchInternational.com

EMPLOYMENT RECORD

Professional geologist between 1990-2012 in Nigeria, South Africa & Mozambique.

- **1.** The Shell Petroleum Development Company of Nigeria Ltd, Exploration Department, Port Harcourt. Nigeria (1990-1991) as a graduate assistant.
- Worldwide Petroleum Services (Teleco Oilfield Services, MWD Division) Port
 Harcourt, Nigeria (1991-1992) as a (Measurement While Drilling Field Engineer/Wellsite
 Drilling Geologist).
- Nirax Nigeria Limited, Port Harcourt, Nigeria (1992-2009), as an environmental hydrogeologist, geohydrologist and Borehole drilling geologist/Consultant (Selfemployed).
- **4.** FoodTents/Heart Capital,Cape Town,South Africa(2011-2012) as an environmental Scientist/environmental geologist(Volunteer job)-
- 5. Melki Drilling & Exploration a division of Melki Plants & Hire CC, Durban, South Africa, (Feb. 2012 to July 2012) as a drilling geologist / Drilling Manager. (Temporary job, worked in Durban & Mozambique.
- **6.** Global green, Cape Town(part time job)-2013 as an environmental scientist/Geologist(groundwater & soil testing)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Between (1991 – 2013)----(21years of work experience)

I have worked, managed, supervised and performed creditably as a professional environmental geologist in Borehole drilling, geo- environmental, geotechnical boring & soil investigation, mining, groundwater exploration, hydrogeology. geohydrology, oil and gas drilling (downhole drilling measurement) services.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Professional Membership And Affiliations.



Elizabeth House, First Floor, Block 2, 39 York Road, London, SE1 7NQ Tel: +44 (0)20 7378 7300 Fax: +44 (0)20 7183 1899

Email: consultant@londonresearchinternational.com www.LondonResearchInternational.com

- Registered No: C-03-2516, (Registered member, The Nigerian Mining and Geosciences Society(NMGS)
- b. Registered No: GEM 0000635 (Registered Council member, The Council of Nigerian Mining Engineers and Geoscientists (COMEG).
- Registered No:CH-2008-00621(Registered member, The Nigerian Association of Hydrogeologists(NAH):an affiliate of International Association of Hydrogeologists.
- d. Registered No: 123242 (Registered Member International Association of Hydrogeologists (IAH) .
- e. Registered No: IND2012/01 (Registered Member Groundwater Association of Kwazulu Natal, South Africa (GAKZN).
- f. Registered No: 3327(Registered Member International Association of Impact Assessment(IAIA),South Africa,Chapter.

Pι	JBL	.ICA	١T	Ol	NS
----	-----	------	----	----	----

Written Project reports on Water & Environmental

LANGUAGES

English